蝴蝶，由今日起你就要独立生活
Butterfly, from now on, you'd be independent.
你要忘记你以前的老公阿全
You'd forget your ex-husband, Chuen.
你要好像一个拳手那样  面对一切的打击
You'd be like a boxer, cope with every challenge.
保持在台上屹立不倒
Never fail!
梦中的公主终于睡醒了
The sleeping princess wakes up
变成美丽的皇后…
and become beautiful queen.
有没有搞错呀？
Kidding!
那么幼稚的东西也写得出
How can you write such silly thing?
变成了美丽的皇后，有甚么幼稚呢？
Silly? Why?
阿全追我那时
When Chuen courted me,
整天都那样跟我讲啦
he always talked to me like this.
你老公阿全是当警察的你也信呀？
Your husband is a cop! How can you trust a cop?
男人追你那时
When a man courts a woman ,
就甚么都说得出啦
he will tell whatever pleasing you.
好像我老公阿飞那样
Like my husband Fred .
他以前说自己是一只没有了脚的鸟呀
He said he was a bird with no legs.
要不断那样在爱情风中飞行
He'll fly in the wind ,
直至到死那天为止
until the day he die.
谁知道同我结婚不够三个月  还不是停飞
And after 3 months of our marriage,
又不见他死？超
he stopped flying. But he doesn't die!
妈咪
- Mom! - Coming.
阿娟 你前天不是说有个做导演的表哥
You said you've a cousin who is a film director.
是
Yes.
做导演的
Art film!
真是够艺术
Really artistic!
蝴蝶，老老实实，大家一场朋友
Be frank, we're friends.
钱我就帮不到你，我会看住你
l can't help you in money,
妈咪
but I'll take care of you.
来啦
- Mom . - Coming.
那衰仔又要见家长
My kid is making trouble again.
拜拜
Bye!
夜叉，那靓女又跑步啦
Jinx, that beauty is now jogging.
看东西呀看东西呀  是呀
- Come on! - Yeah. . .
快点啦  过去看
- Be quick! - Go!
早晨  小姐
Good morning, Miss.
甚么呀？
What is it?
大作家，跑步呀
Are you jogging?
跑步没有益嘛
lt's helpless!
越跑个胸越坠呀  是呀，坠呀坠呀…
- Your breast will drop! - Yeah!
坠不坠关你甚么事呀？
lt's none of your business!
别欺负女人呀你们想怎么样呀？
Don't bully girl! What do you want?
没有我们想帮你拉高它嘛
l just want to help you to tighten it.
夜叉
Jinx!
真够老土
So odd.
吕Sir
Officer Lui.
头还是肚子？
Head or stomach.
我们跟他玩玩而已
We just want to play with her.
大家街坊，又怎么会非礼她呢？
We are neighbours, we won't indecent assault her.
是呀…
We didn't. . .
头还是肚子
Head or stomach?
你这班无赖
You gangsters!
给我再见到你们在这儿
If I see you . . .
横行霸道
bully her again,
我就把你们全抓回去
I'll arrest you all!
原来是警察
Oh! A cop!
黄小姐，我住在你楼上
Miss Wong, l am your neighbour.
我姓吕叫阿奇  吕阿奇？
- My name is Lui , Keith. - Surname Keith?
错，是吕奇
No, Keith Lui !
我见你晚晚开灯
I always see you. . .
开到通宵
working at night.
你习惯在晚间写作的吗？
Are you used to work overnight?
又知我姓黄，又盯著我通宵
He knows my name, he knows I am working overnight too.
不会是好人
He is probably a bad egg.
吕Sir你都算观人入微  再见啦
You have good observation! See you.
我明，我明白  防人之心不可无
I understand! One should be alert is meeting new friends.
那是社会的错
The society makes us behave like this.
我不会怪你的，黄小姐
I won't blame you, Miss Wong!
终于有一天你会明白我吕奇
You'll understand me one day.
是一个出污泥而不染的人
I'm a man of righteousness!
幸好没有人看到
Luckily no one saw it.
有没有搞错呀？  又说要我写艺术片剧本
Kidding! What sort of art film it is?
原来是三级片
It's X-rated script!
理得他咸还是甜啊？
It's a script anyway!
都是剧本而已
love watching X-rated film!
是呀，姐姐呀  妈咪整天租回来看的
Yeah, Auntie, Mom always watches them.
多事啦  你阿妈看都是为了你阿爸而已
Nosy! I watch it for you dad only!
拜拜
Bye!
不知黄小姐明不明白我的心事呢？
I wonder Miss Wong understands me or not.
太过份啦
That's too much!
为甚么我搞到这样的地步？
Why am l that poor!
写三级片？我…
X-rated film?
我一向都是写儿童故事的嘛
I always write novels for children.
真造孽  Call淫贱住家菜
My God! I need to call horny Kuen.
我来
I coming.
那怎么会有新意呢
It's not new!
大象和狗也行吗？
I can write about Snow White and Seven Dwarfs?
二小姐  钱给你
Everything is ready.
这次不用你去  我来
I can go there alone.
哪要早点回来
Go home early.
我也穷呀，又不见你打救一下我
I'm poor! Why don't you save me?
我走了
I have to go.
真够离谱的，找戏来做呀？
It's ridiculous!
找阿全  语气要开心点
I'll call Chuen! With cheerfuI voice!
谁呀？
Who is it?
是我呀
It's me.
你那么晚打电话来干嘛鬼呀？
Why do you call that late?
以后有事劳驾你打来公司
Next time, call to my office.
别打去我家好不好呀？
Don't call to my home, OK?
我老婆知道了
My wife
昨晚跟我吵了一大架
Quarreled severely with me last night!
我也是你老婆呀  不过离了婚而已
I'm your wife too! But ex-wife!
八婆，这次是沙律  下次淋你镪水，走呀
I'll treat you acid next time!
听我讲…不关我事的
It's none of my business!
他打来而已
She called me.
黄小姐，黄小姐
Miss Wong . . .
请问声有没有人在家呀？
May I know anybody home?
既然没有人在，那我就应该…
Since no one is here,
把门先关好
I'd better shut the door first
看看他平时写些甚么也好
to see what she writes.
梦中的公主终于睡醒了  变成美丽的皇后
A waken princess
真够罗曼蒂克的
becomes a queen. Romantic.
这个皇后一定是好寂寞的
She must be a lonely queen.
死啦死啦…
Oh My god! I'm in trouble.
你认得我是谁吗？ 不认得
- Can you recognise me? - No.
你是谁呀？你来我家干嘛呀？
Who are you? Why did you come to my home?
你不要管，你看，我有蔗呀
See! l've sugar cane!
让开让开  让开
Give way. . .
走开…走开呀
- Get lost! - Don't!
你不要乱来呀，你小心呀  我用这根蔗插死你呀
Be careful. Don't push me! I'll kill you with sugar cane.
我也可以干掉你
I can kill you too!
看，我会抛蔗
I know how to throw the sugar cane.
我好厉害的
I am good . See?
好厉害吗？我也行
I know it too!
我一定杀你灭口呀  斩死你
- I'll kill you! - Kill you!
我不来了
I quit!
这是哪儿呀？  吕Sir
- Where is it? - Officer Lui .
干嘛不乘升降机呀？  是呀
Why don't you take the lift?
我想试试看这样是不是快过乘升降机  是吗？
I just want to test whether it is faster of not taking a lift.
别横行霸道的
- Don't bully others. - Yes. . .
蝴蝶，你真没用
Butterfly, you are useless!
爱情事业都失败
You fail both in your career & love life!
过来，过来…
I'm coming.
你看人家多幸福？
See how lucky they are!
我留在这儿献世吗？
Why'd you stay in this cruel world?
我弄伤手指啦  快点去医院啦
I hurt my small finger! Hurry to the hospital!
你别杀他呀
Don't kill him!
我全部东西都给你
I'll give you everything!
我给你  快点啦  走啦
I'll give all to you! Hurry up!
你学人打劫？
What's the matter? You robbed?
谁被打劫呀？ 蝴蝶被打劫呀
- Who is robbed? - Butterfly is robbed!
我现在即刻来呀
I'll be right there.
你怎么样？
How are you?
那么快？不是吧？
Why are you that fast?
我来到门口，我进不去的
I won't go in.
没人，那怎么办？
It's empty, so what'd we do now?
怎么办？拿钥匙开门放下就走啦
Open the door, leave it all then go.
放下就走啦
Put it in & leave!
哗，这些死鬼有钱佬  住那么大间屋都有
What a big home!
你看看…  明明有冷气
Look! There is air conditioner,
吊把风扇在中间，吊脖子呀？
why a fan is needed, for suicide?
妖，你看看，那么大张饭桌
Such a big dinning table?
用来打桌球吗？  你抵得他…
For snooker?
喂，放下东西就走啦
Leave it & go!
你看过了吗？
Have you ever seen such a big house?
那么大间屋子看多一会儿会死吗？
- Why don't we have a visit first? - How long will it take?
妖，厨房呢
I don't have to measure it.
肯定大过我家七、八倍啦
I'm sure the kitchen is 7-8 times bigger than my home.
妖，你看马桶
I don't even have to take a look.
都大过我浴缸啦
I think the toilet is bigger than my bath - tub.
妖，工人房都大过我睡房
The maid's room is bigger than mine.
看够未呀？相当够了
- Have you had enough? - I think so.
再看看主人房
But not after seeing the master bed-room.
妖
Curse it.
妖，那么大张床那够我一个睡呀？
This bed is not big enough for me.
人家是女人，我也是女人
She is woman, so am I .
为甚么我老是那么倒霉呢
Why am l that poor?
妖，你想都不用想呀
You can tell at once!
是那种女人才会甘愿做男人的玩具
These women are willing to be the toys of men.
换了我…？ 有那样多靓衫
If I were. . . So many beautiful clothes,
真是让男人玩足一世我都愿呀，真是
I wish being played by men!
喂，有人回来了  躲起来
Someone is coming back. Hide up!
做什么啊？
Who is it?
梁哥，这儿一千五百万  你数一数
Brother Ti, here is $1 5 million. Have a check.
是他啦
It's him!
阿娟，不如走吧
- Kuen, let's go! - Wait.
对数
That's it.
那些货在这儿，你点算一下
Here are the goods, have a check.
那些货全部从泰国来的
They are from Thailand .
甚么货呀？搞甚么鬼呢？
What are these? What's wrong?
对数了，大佬
That's right!
梁哥你真守信用
You are reliable,
不愧是标哥的头马
that's why you are the right hand of your boss Ah Jia.
你干嘛呀你？你疯了吗？
What are you doing?
丧标的人不能动呀
You can't harm Ah Jia's man.
怕甚么啊，来个货也要钱也要
Why not? We can take both the money & the goods.
梁哥，不关我事
It's none of my business.
我甚么都不知道的  岂有此理
I know nothing! Curse you!
做得好
You've done a good job.
扔了阿祥的尸体落海
Throw Cheung's corpse to sea.
带齐钱和货去菲律宾等我
Take the goods to the Philippines & wait for me.
我回去告诉丧标
I'll tell Ah Jia.
说阿祥吃夹棍  这样就没事了
that Cheung betrayed him . That'll be OK.
我在那边等你
I'll wait you there.
走呀
Let's go. . .
别动
Freeze.
不关我们事的，别吓我
None of our business! Don't scare me!
如果你要杀就杀我啦
If you want to kill, kilI me.
不关我朋友事
Let my friend go!
我保证他不会讲出去
I promise she won't tell others.
你喜欢先奸后杀
Rape first or kill first,
或者是先杀后奸都行  她呀
whatever you like. She. . .
你有没有搞错呀？
What's wrong with you?
我对你两个都没有兴趣
I'm not interested to you,
尤其是你们这种货色
especially your kind .
有你两个陪葬
Having you 2 as companions,
丧标想不信都挺难  不好呀
Ah Jia will never suspect.
走…走  先别走
- Let's go. - Wait.
我们在这儿那么久  一定留下好多指纹
We've stayed here for long, our finger prints must be left.
抹完了才能走，  去
We'd clean them first.
我发神经呀？干嘛连车都抹了？
Am I crazy? Why'd l clean the car?
你在搞甚么呀？
What are you doing?
我故意搞得整个凶案现场
I make it look like a fight
好像他们自相残杀那样
among themselves.
一看不就知道是内l哄了
A civil conflict.
警恶惩奸嫉恶如仇，黑玫瑰留字
Black Rose, who beats crimes!
就等警方找个饱
Let the police spend time to look for Black Rose.
你以为现在是粤语长片吗？
Don't you think it's film?
嫉字都写错呀，走啦
You spelled the word wrongly!
等等呀，这张纸有指模呀
HoId it! There is finger print on the paper.
快点啦，明仔的老师又要我见家长呀
Hurry up. . . My son's teacher wants to see me.
好…
Great. . .
超，你干嘛门也不关呀
Why don't you shut the door?
黑玫瑰？你耍我呀
Are you fooling me?
黑玫瑰是甚么字头呀？
Who is Black Rose?
够胆吃我丧标的夹棍？
You dare to rob from me?
大哥，我没有骗你
I am not cheating you!
你不信就找人收收风
If you don't believe, get some information yourself.
她们是两个女孩
They are 2 girls.
我亲眼见她们拿走了钱和货的
I did see them take away our money & goods.
帮我找九叔来，我有事问他
Ask uncle Kau here, I want to ask him something.
好
Yes.
黑玫瑰，够胆碰我丧标的东西
Black Rose dared to trouble me.
斩开他几十块呀
I'll chop them into pieces!
陈Sir，楼上大门发现的指模
We've found finger prints on the main door.
在五十年代
There was a heroine
的确是有个侠盗黑玫瑰
called Black Rose in the 50's.
她专门劫富济贫
She robbed the rich
很受贫苦大众拥护
and helped the poor.
后来导演楚原
The director Chor Yuen
为了纪念这个侠盗
in order to memorize her.
还找他老婆南红来饰演她呢
He directed a film with his wife acted Black Rose.
受人拥护又怎么样？
But she committed crime,
总之她犯法就要抓  进来
so we'd arrest her. Come in!
Sir，疑犯在凶案
Sir, the suspect left. . .
留下的指模
the fingerprints.
经过电脑分析
They are analysed by the computer.
已经知道她们是谁
We now know who she is.
这些就是她们的资料
Here are their information.
警方现正悬红五十万元
The Black Rose is wanted by the cops,
缉捕女飞贼黑玫瑰归案
with $500,000 offered.
如果有人发现女飞贼黑玫瑰的线索
If you get any clue of the Black Rose,
有你个衰样，NWith your picture,
我不怕挖不到你出来\
I'm sure to get you .
阿梁，我一个礼拜之后回来
Brother, I'll return on week later.
到时你别跟我说
Don't teIl me
还没搞掂那件事
you can't handle it.
行啦我会做啦
OK! I know what to do.
大佬
Boss.
我走了之后替我盯紧点
Keep an eye on it when l'm leaving.
师父在上，弟子飘红在下
Dear Master, you student, Piu Hung,
我今日看完电视新闻
is feeling miserable
都不知多伤心
after watching TV.
发现有几个无耻之徒
Few shameless rascals
她们竟敢冒认师父的名义
dare to frame you
出来做些伤天害理的事
to commit crimes.
所以我决定…我决定…
So I decided . . .
我决定甚么了？
What have I decided?
说著说著又不记得了
I forget!
糟了，师父约了我去哪儿喝茶呢？
Curse it! Where should I go to meet my master?
挑，你想帮师父找出真凶
You want to find out the murderer
就干掉那混帐东西
and kill him for revenge.
我用得著你提呀，我想著想著…
I need no hints from you.
干不干掉是由我这个掌门人说了算
To kill or not, I'd give the order! I am the headmaster,
几时轮到你说话呀？
It's not your turn to give any order.
怪不得你练功练傻了
You deserve being crazy!
怪不得当年奇哥都怕了你啦
No wonder Keith is scared & left.
乱说，奇哥B喱巴啦的是我
Nonsense!
喜欢你？ 劳驾你自己看看啦
He loves you, doesn't he?
奇哥跟我都不知多好呀
Keith & I are perfect couple!
不是你在这儿瞎捣乱，奇哥会走掉？
It's all because of you, so Keith left without a word .
你骗人，这个是吴孟达
You are cheating me! He is Man-tat Ng.
他是吴孟达？
He is Man-tat Ng?
对不起，记错了  是周星驰
Sorry, I am wrong. He is Stephen Chow.
你傻啦？你说奇哥是周星驰
You nuts!
你才傻呀，奇哥当然不是周星驰啦
You nuts! Keith is not Stephen Chow,
这个才是周星驰嘛
This is Stephen Chow!
与其被他气死，不如我先玩残你
You'll make me rage sooner or later. Let me fool you instead!
我在说甚么？
What am I talking?
你欠大耳窿钱嘛  是谁呀？
- You are the loan shark! - Who is it?
你还养了个小白脸
You have an adonis.
你说抛出身子去杜老志帮他填数的
You'd work in night club to pay the debt of him.
杜老志？我去茶舞还是夜舞呀？
Night club? Isn't it day shift or night shift?
师姐，你去不去呀？
Are you going?
你快点换衫啦
Get change now,
你男友打死你都有份呀
or your boyfriend will beat you!
打死我那么凶呀？
Isn't he that vicious?
师姐，那我男友是谁啊？
Who is my boyfriend then?
你先告诉我啦
Let's finish it first, OK?
你老是跟我说话说一半，真不够意思
You always stop the conversation In such an odd way!
我沦落风尘  怎么我学人养小白脸吗？
Am I a club girl? Did I pay for my boyfriend?
死了，我男友是谁都不记得了
I forget who is my boyfriend!
我失忆症愈来愈严重了
My memory is getting worse & worse!
糟了  我的药放在哪儿呀？
Curse it! Where did I put my medicine?
明明放在这儿的，没理由的
I did put it here!
是不是在卓底呀？
I forgot to flush the toilet.
劳驾你把这个给我
Please give me this
山东佬，给我一斤瘦肉，搭块猪头骨
I want one catty of pork and bone please,
老板，我要三包榨菜
Please give me 3 pieces of mustard root spiced .
等我自己挑
I'll choose it myself.
一样啊
It's just the same.
我挑跟你挑会一样吗？
Isn't it?
每块都差不多啦
They are almost the same.
老板，大新闻呀  甚么大新闻呀？
- Big news! - What?
女飞侠重出江湖呀  是不是呀？
- Black Rose is showing up again! - Really?
现在电视都在播啦
Now, they are on TV.
凶案现场的三名死者
There are 3 corpses at the scene.
其中一名姓李的男人是十大通缉犯
One of them is named Lee, is a wanted criminal.
而姓郑的女死者
And the other 2,
和姓赵的男死者
Cheng, and Chiu.
都有多次的贩毒纪录
They have records of drugs trafficking.
黑玫瑰事后…
After the black rose
我从小就知道黑玫瑰好棒啦
I knew Black Rose, she was famous when I was small.
她当然厉害啦  我们当她是神那么拜的
We worship her!
这三个家伙可真该死的
These 3 guys deserved it!
警方现在悬红50万元
The Black Rose is wanted by the cops,
通缉女飞贼黑玫瑰归案
with $500,000 offered.
那样像呀？
They look like the same!
原来黑玫瑰喜欢吃榨菜的
Black Rose loves eating this!
就这三块啦
I want these.
我不会为了五十万出卖侠士
I won't betray the heroine with $500,000.
大家义气子女江湖救急
We are men of righteousness.
你喜欢就整缸拿去吧
Take all if you like it.
干嘛要我整缸拿去呀？我只要三个
Why should I?
你只要三个
I will feel very happy
我已经很满意了
if you take these.
以后有人问我，我就跟他说
I'll tell others that.
说黑玫瑰在我这儿拿了三块榨菜
Black Rose took 3 pieces from me,
我多有面子呀
I'm proud of it!
甚么黑玫瑰呀？  你看看
- How? - Look!
妖
What the. . .
黑玫瑰妖我们呀
Is that the Black Rose?
去…快点追
- Let's check. - Come on.
不是呀，我说过我不是
I'm not her.
妖，我都说我不是黑玫瑰了
I'm not the Black Rose!
妖，电视都拍了你的样子出来啦  搞错呀？
But the news said you are the Black Rose!
你是黑玫瑰？
Are you Black Rose?
你以为我想做黑玫瑰吗？
Don't you think I wish to be Black Rose?
我老婆是黑玫瑰呀
My wife is Black Rose!
恭喜  恭喜呀，你老婆的名号那么响
Congratulation. . . Your wife is so famous!
你是他老公
You are her husband,
又在我们保险公司做事
and you're working in our insurance co. ,
客人一定很放心
the clients will be pleased.
由今日起，我升你做总经理
You are promoted to General Manager now!
恭喜你…
- I? - Congratulation. . .
多谢…
Thank you. . .
谁是周维娟的老公林超呀？
Who is the husband of Chow Wai Kuen?
他
He is.
你是嘛？跟我回警署
Please follow us to the police station.
阿Sir
Why?
干嘛要回警署呀？Sir
- Sir. . . - What is it?
香港地方上落真是快
- What a great and quick change! - Yes.
不如我升你做总经理
Why don't you be the General Manager?
别搞
Forget it!
喂？找谁呀？
Who are you looking for?
你是不是找周维娟呀？
Are you looking for Chow Wai Kuen?
来了
Coming.
阿伯，你找谁呀？
Who are you looking for?
蝴蝶  啊？阿娟呀？
- Butterfly! - Kuen!
快点关上窗帘，关上门啦，快点啦
Close the curtain & the door, quick!
好
OK!
你站在外面叫甚么鬼啊？
What are you doing outside?
妖  去哪儿弄这么件东西呀
Where did you get it?
庐导演那儿拿回来的
Hou Hsiao-hsien lent it to me.
你知不知呀，新闻说你是黑玫瑰呀？
Do you know, you are said to be the Black Rose.
当然知道啦，都是因为你
Sure! It's all because of you.
搞到我老公连我也恼了
My hubby is mad at me too.
你干嘛那么凶？
Why are you that mad?
人家本来不知多开心
I was happy in the past.
天天都在家煮饭带孩子
I was a housewife,
老公不知多疼我
my husband loved me.
现在弄得我躲起来又不见得人
But I'd hide myself now.
连老公都误会我
My hubby misunderstands me!
你自己没有老公就好
You are single! Don't jealous!
干嘛连累人家呢
Why you dragged me down!
你一世人都是那么失败？
You are always a failure!
你怪我呀？
Are you blaming me?
黄小姐
Miss Wong!
吕Sir，为甚么你会有我家钥匙？
Why do you have my keys?
这件事是这样  等我先关上门
May I explain? Let me shut the door first.
吕Sir？
Officer Lui.
那日你无意中跌了一条钥匙
You dropped your key one day.
我就无意中捡到了
I picked it up by chance.
所以我今日特意买两条…
So I buy 2 tickets. . .
这位是你贵亲呀？
Who is he?
我伯父呀  阿伯父
- My uncle. - Uncle.
怎么他那么抖？
He is trembling!
是呀，他患了帕金逊症嘛
He's got senile disorder.
现在我要去拉K呀  伯父，我帮你？
Butterfly, go with me.
拉屎呀…  急屎呀…
Hurry up!
蝴蝶，陪我去拉屎  快点啦，拉屎呀，急呀
Let me go with you.
这些事不是女人做的
Leave it to me.
我们男人老狗，等我来
I am a man, let me do it.
我帮你揭起厕所板
Come on, uncle. I'll help you.
又帮你拉开拉链  来了，伯父
Then, I'll help you zip up.
现在不急屎啦急尿呀…  我要撒尿呀撒尿
Thank you. . . I want to piss only.
那你拉啊
Then you pull it
你别望住我，望住我，我拉不出的  别望啦
Don't look at me, or I can't piss. Don't!
伯父，既然你拉不出
As you are unable to piss,
要不要我帮帮忙呀？
may I help you?
出来了，在出来了
I can do it myself.
伯父，你好热气啊，那样多泡
So many bubbles.
味道还很像洗洁精呢
- It seems to be detergent! - It is normal today.
糟了…
Oh, No
伯父，撒完尿就要吃东西啦
After going to the toilet,
吃饭了，蝴蝶喂我吃饭
you better come to eat now.
先坐下
- Butterfly, help me. - Sit down first.
不用…  不用了吕Sir
- No. - No, officer Lui .
你回警署做事吧，我喂他
You'd better go to work, I'll do it.
不怕的，我喂也吃完
It's alright. l'll do it.
喂自己都还有时间
I have plenty of time.
我伯父他吃饭
My uncle wants song
要人唱歌给他听的
to accompany his dinner too.
不如让我喂他吧  是呀…还要唱歌呀  不用麻烦你了
Let me do it. I won't bother you .
你鬼马啦  好，我唱
You naughty! OK, I'll sing you a song!
♪ 小宝宝，吃蛋糕
Baby, eat the rice.
♪ 饭仔叔叔喂到
I am feeding you.
♪ 吃过长大，大个没有坏
You will grow up soon.
♪ 饭仔最好
It's delicious.
看看你，你没事吧
See, are you OK?
原来是吃得太饱，吃滞了
You have eaten too much.
是呀，你上班吧，我喂他得了
You'd better leave, l can feed him myself.
那，黄小姐，我先走
Well, I am leaving.
别喂得他太饱  好
- Fine. - Don't give him too much.
你费心了，再见
- See you. - Bye!
再见
Uncle, bye-bye.
好惹不惹？
Why do you make friends
惹这么个死警察回来
with this cop?
心地好就得了，理得他警不警察的
He is kind hearted anyway.
警察靠得住，母猪都会上树呀
We should not trust any cop!
你不记得你以前的老公也是警察来的
Do you remember, your ex-husband is a cop too.
那也是，听电话呀
Yes. . . A calI.
我换衫
I'll get change.
喂，黄小姐，我是吕奇
Miss Wong, l am Keith Lui .
甚么事呀？吕Sir
What's the matter?
我刚才在你门口外面斗争了好久
I have a severe struggle in front of your door,
看看应不应该抓你们两个
See if I should arrest you two or not.
我知道她是黑玫瑰
I know she is the Black Rose.
那你还打电话来干嘛呀？
So why are you calling?
因为我是一个警察
I am a cop,
我已经打了电话回警署
So I reported to the HQ.
他们5分钟之后就会到
They wiIl arrive in 5 minutes.
你们由后面走吧
Go from the rear door.
我上来…
I came. . .
本来是为了
to apologize
昨晚的事道歉
for last night,
还想约你看刘德华演唱会
and want to invite you to a concert.
借这个机会，大家谈谈心事
To make use of this chance, to understand each other better.
我恐怕我己经没有这个机会
But I am afraid there will be no chance.
不过如果你想找我
But if you want to find me,
我已经将电话写在演唱会的票后面
I have written my number at the back of the ticket.
那张票就放在茶几上面
Which is put on the table.
保重
Take care.
那边
That way!
现在你和我家都有警察守住
There are cops in our homes.
我们回不去？
We can't go back.
这样藏去也不是办法
We can't hide ourselves for life.
我们身上又没有钱
But we have no money.
想说乞钱又不够胆露面
We can't even beg for money.
这样下去难道真是要我们去打劫呀
Or should we rob?
好，就决定这样做
OK, let's make it a deal.
讲笑而已，你别那样认真啦
Kidding! Don't be that serious.
一不做二不休
By hook or by crook!
大大的做一次
We rob
然后远走高飞
and run away.
等到安全的时候
Whenever I am safe,
就接我老公和孩子一起走
I'll pick up my family.
阿娟，你冷静点好不好呀？
Kuen, stay calm , OK?
现在那几个家伙不是我们杀的嘛
We didn't murder them.
迟早会水落石出的
The cops will find out the truth.
蝴蝶，我不同你
Butterfly, I am different from you.
你一个人你可以怎么都行
You can do whatever you want, cause you are single.
我不可以再走错一步
I can't!
如果警方真以为是我做的
If the cops think it was done by me.
我以后就没机会见我老公
I will have no chance to see
和孩子了
my family again.
我不会连累你的
I won't drag you down.
我自己去做就行了  你放心啦
I will do it myself. Don't worry.
你这样讲是甚么意思？
What do you mean?
意思就是看死你不会让我一个人去做
You won't let me do alone.
我们情同姊妹嘛  你去我都要去
We are good friends. We must go together.
都说吃定你了
I am sure you'll do it.
让我去啦
Let me go with you!
我也没你办法
I can't stop you.
你真要逼我去做
If you force me so,
我就陪你啦
I will help.
多谢你，你真是好人
Thank you, you are so kind .
我们现在就去
Let's go now.
别动，打劫
Stop, rob!
不要哭呀  再哭我毒哑你的
- Don't cry! - Or else I'll hit you .
信不信我一枪就打爆你呀？
Trust me or not? I'll kill you.
他撒尿呀？
Pissing?
B仔，你乖啦，别哭啦
Good boy, don't cry.
快点拿橡皮筋来捆他的小弟弟啦
Tight it up now.
别理他，快点走啦
Forget them , let's go!
有没有搞错？第一单就那样不顺利
Kidding,
不顺利
we fail!
妖
Shitf
蝴蝶，我们都算厉害了
Butterfly, we are so great!
我想香港开埠以来  都未试过有人打劫猪红粥
I think no robbers have robbed soup before.
给多一次机会自己
Give us one more chance.
吃饱点，再来过
Try again after the food .
不好了吧？
Kidding?
钱我就搞掂了，看你了
I'm fine, it's all up to you
这个鬼佬身光颈靓
He seems to be rich.
就这个啦  一会儿后巷见
- Our target! - See you in the back lane.
跟我来
Follow me.
去
Go!
是你们？ 是他？
- You again! - It's them!
追
Chase after them!
现在怎么办？
What shall we do now?
大佬，没有呀，不见呀
Disappear!
由他吧，别讲那样多，回去再说
Let her go, let's go back now.
好
Let's go!
你上我的车来干嘛呀？
Why do you get in my car?
我想顺路载你们回家而已
I think you will give me a ride.
你们是谁？
Who are you?
我们都不认得就想学人扮黑玫瑰？
You don't even know us, how dare you pretend to be Black Rose?
信不信我插死你？
Don't you believe I'll kill you?
等我这个掌门人来问他
I'll question her.
你到底吃饭没有？  啊？
Have you eaten?
真烦？
It's troublesome.
师姐，你再是那么瞎闹
If you still make trouble here,
别怪我出掌门铃呀
Don't blame me of using the Master's Bell.
你吓唬我呀？
Are you telling me?
她撞邪呀？
Haunted?
这些是本派的门规
This is our school's regulation,
见铃如见先师
the bell represents our master.
一听见铃声响，就要耍小连拳了
Once hear the bell rings, she should practise kung-fu.
现在到底是我问你还是#S*…
Am I asking you . . .
到底黑玫瑰是你甚么人？
What relationship between Black Rose and you?
你是谁那么厉害要我说给你听？
Why should I tell you?
我不认识黑玫瑰
I don't know her.
你再不说黑玫瑰和黄飞鸿是甚么关系
If you don't tell me the relationship
你就这辈子
between you and Wong Fei-hong,
都别指望出去
You can never go out.
甚么黄飞鸿呀？
What Wong Fei-hong?
你不就是黄飞鸿  我是黄飞鸿？
- You are Wong Fei-hong. - I'm Wong Fei-hong?
有没有搞错呀？
Kidding!
好
Fine.
我刚才问你甚么话？
What did I just ask you?
你刚才不是说介绍个医生给我？
You said you would introduce a doctor to me.
没有呀
No.
没有？没有你进来我家干嘛呀？
So why did you break in my house?
我什么时候自己来你家，是你抓我来的
You took me here.
我呸
Crap!
无端端捉你来我家？
Why did I do such nonsense thing?
我嫌米饭便宜呀？
I have a lot of things to do.
你硬是不肯介绍医生给我是不是？
Don't you refuse to introduce me a doctor?
有  刘定坚医生
Yes. Doctor Ma.
刘医生好嘛？
Isn't he good?
好，我的女朋友隆胸都是他做的
Sure, Veronica Yip went to him for plastic surgery.
隆胸？我几时说给你听我要隆胸的？
I don't want any plastic surgery.
师姐，他硬是要耍人
Sister, she wants to fool me.
由得你怎么处置他
Fix her whatever you want.
#S*…
这家伙不会功夫
She doesn't know kung-fu .
看来不是他扮师父
I don't think she is the one who framed our master.
顶得两搥
She can stand it.
他疯了，他戳我屁股两刀呀
You crazy! You hurt my bottom!
怎么那样重手呀？
So severely!
那妞一天在我手上
Since I have got the girl,
她朋友在外面都不敢爆料出来
her friend won't tell anything to the cops.
只要你帮我盯住警察那边
You should keep an eye on the cops.
过了这个礼拜，等丧标回来之前
After this week, before Ah Jia coming back,
我一定会出货给他
I'll ship the goods away.
到时就算丧标知道了
Even Ah Jia knows it,
他都找不到我啦
he can't find me.
黎Sir，你等我好消息啦
Wait for my good news, Superintendent Lai.
大佬，那小妞在下面呱呱吵
Boss, the girl is shouting downstairs.
开门呀开门呀
Open the door. . .
好辛苦呀，你进来啦  进来呀
I am not feeling well, come in please.
甚么事？
What's the matter?
你进来，进来再讲
Come in first!
你出来  你进来  你出来
- Come out! - Come in!
你不进来我怎么出来呀？
How can I come out if you don't come in?
你不出来我怎么进来呀？
If you don't come out, how can I come in?
进来呀  不进
- Come in! - No!
你有没有搞错？
Are you kidding?
那么辛苦你都不进来
Why do you refuse to come in?
你想怎么呀？
What do you want?
你想怎么呀
Do you really know how to act?
妖，人家都不是那么设计的
It's out of my expectation!
发神经
Crazy!
趁记得先写下来
I'll mark it down when my memory is still fresh.
干嘛呀你？
What are you doing?
墙
Wall.
柱
Pillar.
电视
TV.
喂，我怎么看呀？  这位是师姐
- How can l watch it? - She is my senior.
你傻呀？ 我是飘红
- Are you nuts? - I am Piu Hung.
僵尸先生
Mr. Vampire.
茶煲响，水滚茶靓
The water boils.
电话又响
I'll go and answer the phone.
吕Sir我现在成个人都乱了
Lui, I don't know what to do now,
不知怎么办呀？
what shall I do?
你留在原来地方，千万别走开
Stay where you are, don't leave.
我即刻赶来
I'll be right there.
佳人有难，我一定要去
My girlfriend is in trouble, I must go.
不过要先打扮一下
But well dressed.
甚么伤成这样呀？
You hurt!
进来…  给人软禁你？
Come in. . . You are kidnapped?
哪儿有人在这儿呀？  你别走呀，进来呀，进来呀
Where are the criminals? Don't go, come in. . .
哪有人啊？你别连阿Sir都耍呀
Where are they?
我没有耍你呀，Sir
Don't cheat us.
我没有
No, l didn't!
他们真是插了我两刀嘛
They did stab me twice!
插你两刀？你还会站在这儿？
If so, why are you still standing here?
现在人呢？
Where are they now?
他们明明在这儿的
They were here!
两个死家伙
Curse them!
真是有两个死东西在这儿
Oh my god! There are 2 corpses here!
他们怎么插你两刀呀？  你别动呀
How can they hurt you? Don't move!
不是我杀？
I didn't kill them.
你别动呀
Don't move!
我现在Call伙记来帮手
I'll report and call for help.
大佬，有事慢慢讲呀
Sir, let's stay calm.
是我杀的  你
- I do it. - You!
你想不到吧？
Can you guess so?
大佬，你千万别手软呀
Please don't!
你们的事我当看不到
I won't tell others about your business.
黑玫瑰？  她们
Black Rose? They are the Black Roses,
你和黑玫瑰有甚么关系？
What relationship do you have with the Black Rose?
说，为甚么吃我夹棍？
Tell me, why did you rob my goods?
我哪有吃你们夹棍
I don't know
我都不知你说甚么？
what are you talking about!
我想著和阿娟还点东西给人而已
I just wanted to return something to that man.
谁知道会撞到你们在这儿交易啊
I didn't know you were dealing business.
我以为看戏才会有黑玫瑰
I think the Black Rose only appeared in movie.
我都不认识黑玫瑰
I don't know Black Rose.
我留低张字条，想著转移警方的目标
I left the message in order to shift the attention of the police.
现在还害死了两位前辈
But I don't mean to drag them down .
是我贪玩，对不起
I am sorry, I don't mean to.
我以后不敢了，对不起呀
I won't do it again! Sorry!
对不起呀，两位，对不起呀？
Sorry, I am sorry!
终于水落石出
We get the truth now.
为甚么会这样？？
What's wrong?
为甚么？假人来的
They are fake.
等你见识一下
I will show you
我们玫瑰秘笈里面的易容术啦
the make-up technic written in our Rose Book.
先脱了假脚
I'll remove the fake foot first.
原来你们刚才是试我
Oh, you are testing me.
我见你刚才对住两个假人
You cried sorrowfully
都哭哭啼啼
for 2 fake men.
可见你这人心地善良
So I can tell you are kind hearted.
正所谓…  识英雄重英雄
Let's say hero respects hero.
你敬我一尺，我敬你一丈
You respect me, I respect you more.
好，黄飞鸿，我就放你广州l啦
OK, Wong Fei-hong, I'll let you go back you Canton.
前辈，我是姓黄，叫蝴蝶呀
Master, my name is Butterfly Wong.
有人
Somebody is coming.
黄小姐…黄小姐
Miss Wong . . .
黄小姐
Miss Wong!
别搞呀
Stop it!
我Hi，我再Hi
Try again!
有机关？
Trap?
不是吧，这种年代还有机关？
Kidding! We are in a modern era.
五龙吐珠？
Pearls from 5 dragons?
哗，这儿是不是片场呀？
Is it a shooting site?
现在是不是在拍戏啊？
Are you filming?
他藏在哪儿呀？  Cut呀Cut呀
Where is she hiding? Cut!
奇哥？
Keith?
奇哥？这名字那么熟？
Why the name seems so familiar?
快点开机关
ReIease the trap!
他是谁来著？师姐
Who is he?
师妹连奇哥都不记得，那就对了
She forgets who is Keith, that's good .
师姐，你讲啦
Tell me.
他…  他不是你阿爸吗
He. . . is your dad.
啊？他是我阿爸？他…
My dad?
他离开了我二十年
He left me for 20 years,
终于舍不得我  今晚回来找我
now he can't forget me. He comes back for me.
阿爸回来找你？
He comes back for you?
为甚么他不找阿妈呢？
Why doesn't he search for mom?
我不就是你阿妈
I am your mom!
你是我阿妈？  你不是师姐吗？
You are my mom? Aren't you my senior?
没错，当年奇哥离开我那时
Yes, when Keith left me,
他不知我已经珠胎暗结
he didn't know I was pregnant.
我为了保存奇哥的后代
To keep our baby.
我偷偷地走进一个深山找了个山窿
I hid myself into a cave.
经过冬去春来一段日子
After few months,
我终于生了你
I gave birth to you.
当时没有人帮我接生
No one helped me in delivery.
你的脐带都是我用口咬断的
So I bited off the umbilical cord of yours.
所以，你有个乳名就叫做咬脐
So, your nick-name is umbilical cord.
阿妈，甚么看上来
But in appearance,
我们的年纪都差不多啊
I am as old as you.
无他的，一个人少出去跑
I seldom fooling around .
加上后天补养下
I also received some minor plastic surgeries.
好好多的
They make me look young.
妈  我真是觉得温暖
Mom! I feel warm!
今晚我一定要得到奇哥
I want Keith tonight!
一定来个生米煮成熟饭
To make him mine!
阿女，你给我拎这东西出去
Baby, take this thing out!
我有话跟你阿爸讲
I have something to talk to your dad.
跟我来，姐姐
Follow me, sister.
怎么一认是女，就年青那样多了
She looks young at once.
姐姐，你给人点了穴呀
You can't move now.
我要捉里面那个男人
I want to chase the man.
你怎么样呀？
How are you?
无谓挣扎了
Stop it!
你的失忆症愈来愈严重
You memory is getting worse and worse.
谁说我失忆呀？
Who say so?
好，我问你，你头戴住那个叫甚么？
What's on your head?
好我再问你
Why do you carry the bell
你腰间别着个铃叮做什么的？
on your waist?
谁说是铜铃呀，是掌门铃  错
- It's the Master's Bell. - Wrong!
明明写著的
It's written!
铃是会响的，不响怎么会叫做铃呢？
It can't ring, why is it called Bell?
你迟早都是我的人呀
What do you want now?
你现在想怎么样呀？
- You'll be mine sooner or later. - Go away.
What are you doing?
我这次一定要得到你
I want you now.
你不好过来，  走开
Go away. I don't want to be in a movie.
听不听到呀？
Listen?
我听到了，  别摇啦
Yes, stop it.
八婆，你好了呀
Hag, stop it.
你这负心汉  枉我那样爱你
You are heartless. I love you so much,
你叫我做八婆？
but you called my hag.
等我杀了你
I'll kill you.
你现在想怎么样呀？
What are you doing? Help.
你没良心，等我挖了你的心出来呀  阿妈，你干嘛打阿爸呀？
You are heartless.
枉我那样爱你，你那样对我？
Do you understand the feeling of keeping one's own sad feelings?
锁他落地牢
How can something like this happen?
明天杀了他
I'll kill him tomorrow.
阿爸？甚么？
- Daddy! - What?
怎么你的样子  那么像我认识的一个人呢
You look like someone I know.
阿爸？ 阿爸？
- Daddy! - Daddy?
放我出去呀…  放我出去呀
Let me go! . . .
放我出去呀
I have to go.
我堂堂一个维护法纪的警察
I'm a cop.
他居然够胆禁锢我
How dare you lock me here!
黄小姐，这两个究竟是甚么人来的？
Who are they? Miss Wong!
这两个不就是黑玫瑰的传人
They are the students of Black Rose.
黑玫瑰？你以为我是小孩子吗？  黑玫瑰
Black Rose? Are you kidding?
其实今次走不走得了
Can we escape or not.
就全靠你了  甚么意思呀？
- It all depends on you . - Why?
虽然他锁了你在这儿
Although they lock you up here,
但是我知道她们很喜欢你
I know they love you.
啊？不是吧？
Kidding!
甚么不是呀？你的假老婆呀
It's true! You "lover"!
简直当你是她以前的初恋情人奇哥呀
She treats you as her 1 st love - Keith!
奇哥？
Keith!
♪ 当年相恋意中人
"My lover had"
♪ 大家性情近
"my kind of personality."
♪ 夫妇爱根极亲密
"The husband and wife deeply loved"
♪ 心心相印互信任
"and trusted each other."
♪ 月底花间相偎依
"We felt lucky to meet and"
♪ 共喜有缘份
"hugged each other under the moon."
♪ 恩爱百般愿比翼
"We loved each other deepIy and"
♪ 痴心一缕共订盟
"promised to stay together forever."
♪ 喜逢爹妈倍精神
"Parents were in good spirits."
♪ 内心快乐无憾
"I was so happy about it."
♪ 朝晚眷恋共欢叙
"We always stayed together"
♪ 天天相见互慰问
"and greeted each other every day."
♪ 立心栽花花不香
"What I did on purpose was in vain."
♪ 还反惹愁恨
"It just made me sad."
♪ 只怨爱海起风波
"I could only blame that love changed"
♪ 一朝生变断爱盟
"and the promise couldn't be kept."
我自有我的办法
I have a way to deal the situation.
吕Sir，你有甚么办法呀？
Officer Lui! What is the method?
♪ 恩情于今化烟云
"The love was lost."
♪ 未许再续情份
"There is no chance to start again."
♪ 空有爱丝万千丈
"I had a lot of affections for her,"
♪ 可惜都已尽化恨
"but they now turn to hatrad."
♪ 枉抛相思枉痴恋
"I once loved her very much"
♪ 恨卿心太忍
"but she was so hard-hearted ."
♪ 只有叹惜旧欢似梦
"It's a pity that it became a dream"
♪ 早经消散莫再寻  早经消散莫再寻…
"and couldn't be found again."
你听我解释  那事件是…
Please listen to my explanation. The story is. . .
吕Sir呀
Officer Lui!
你还唱这首歌来骗我？
You still cheat me with that song!
不得了啦…  阿爸，阿妈好伤心呀
It's big news! Daddy, mom is very sad .
她说不想做人了
She doesn't want to live.
打得我那么伤
Being beaten like this,
我也不想做人呀
I don't want to live too.
阿妈打得你好伤呀？  是呀，好伤呀
- Did she hurt you severely? - Yes!
你吃了它
Eat this!
不是嘛？
No.
受伤用得著吃那样多跌打丸呀？
Why do l have to take these?
不是跌打丸呀  是砒霜呀
These are not for curing. But are arsenic for killing!
砒霜？
Arsenic?
既然你和阿妈都说不想做人
Since you don't want to live.
那就不如双双殉情了吧
Why not suicide?
就好像胭脂扣那样
Like Romeo & Juliet.
你是十二少，阿妈是如花
You are Romeo & mom is Juliet.
来，趁热吃  我不吃…
- Come on. - No!
好了，阿妈，阿爸吃光了
Bravo! Mom , dad has taken all of them.
他说最喜欢都是你，好了
He said he loved you most.
麦提沙来的
It's sweet chestnut.
麦提沙？他干嘛逼我吃麦提沙呀？
Why did she force me to eat sweet chestnut?
黄小姐  你没事嘛  我没事
- Miss Wong, are you OK? - I'm fine.
我们两都算有缘有份啦
It's fate for us to meet again!
以前我们就住楼上楼下
We were neighbours.
想不到现在就变了左邻右里
Now, we live together too.
我想你以前住得舒服过现在
I think it's less comfortable now?
都是我累了你
It's me who dragged you down!
你千万别怪责自己
Don't blame yourself!
我是自愿的
It's my own wish!
蝴蝶呀蝴蝶，你清醒点
Butterfly! Wake up!
他是警察呀
He is a cop!
你千万不好再盲目的跌入  这些蝴蝶网呀
Don't faIl in this butterfly trap!
对了，说是说
You are living alone.
怎么你的家人不在香港吗
Where are your family members?
我先生在欧州做事，很少回来
My husband is working in Europe.
你先生？
Your husband.
是呀，我先生在间外国出版社
He is an editor of a foreign publishing co.
主编童话故事
for nursery tales.
他这人很有童心
He is a man
人人都说他是小孩子来的
who can't change his boyish disposition.
吕Sir，你干嘛撞头进墙呀？
What're you doing?
我想通了，这条叫做苦肉计
This is a trick!
如果我不是这样做
If not so.
那两个女人
They won't trust me
一定不信我对她们一片痴心
that they are in my heart.
只要她们相信
Only they believe,
我们就有一线生机
we'll have chance.
吕Sir  叫我阿奇啦
- Officer Lui . - Call me Keith.
我读得书少，不会讲童话故事
I am not well educated, I don't know how to tell children's story.
不过出这种馊主意
However, l watched a lot of movies.
我还有三两下的
I'm expert!
去啦，大声叫啦  说我纯情自杀啦
Go! Shout loudIy for help! Say I'm going to suicide!
去啦
Go!
救命呀，有人纯情自杀呀，快点来
HeIp! Somebody suicides!
有人纯情自杀呀，救命呀
HeIp!
吃麦提沙都会死人？
What? Sweet chestnut can kill?
阿爸，你怎么呀？阿爸
Daddy! How are you?
你还不快点去拿止血散？
Why don't you get some medicine?
别吵呀
Shut up!
止血散…
Medicine. . .
死了，不记得在哪儿了
I forget where is it?
不怕，写著那些就是了
There is a sticker on it!
那么大包止血散呀？
So big!
你别吵了，我点了你的穴
Shut up! I've pressed your sinus,
没理由痛的
you will be painless.
止血散来了  你快点帮他止血呀
- Here comes the medicine! - Help him to stop bleeding first!
省得弄脏了地方
Don't dirty my place!
你不原谅我  我做人还有甚么意义？
If you don't forgive me, you'd better let me die.
原谅你？一句原谅你
Forgive you?
我就等足你廿几年
Because of forgiving you, I've waited for 20 years.
你知不知你多么狠心
Don't you know how cruel are you?
我的初恋就是给你骗了
You cheated my 1 st love.
当时我只不过是十三岁
I was only 1 3!
你十三岁就生我了吗？阿妈  好痛呀
You gave birth to me at 1 3?
练功的人身子好
I'm strong
别说十三岁  就算是八岁…
because I always practise kung-fu! Even I was 8. . .
你怎么搞得他这样呀？
What's wrong with you?
我帮他止血嘛
I just want to stop him from bleeding!
你用红毛泥帮他止血呀？
You use cement?
你傻啦？你跟我来呀，来了
Are you nuts? Follow me.
别动啊  好痛呀
- Don't move! - It hurts!
我叫你别动嘛
Don't move!
洗了就不痛了  你说甚么？
- It won't hurt after washing it. - I can't hear!
自己洗
Wash it yourseIf.
红毛泥进耳朵了
I guess the cement has entered my ear.
来，抹了它
Wipe it.
劳驾
Thanks.
♪ 自悔轻挑讲错话
"I'm sorry that l said the wrong"
♪ 累你哭泣声哽咽
"words and made you cry."
♪ 原谅了我诸般错，快回家
"Please forgive me and go home."
♪ 恨你多多假说话，N"I hate that you lied to me"
♪ 恨你口多心太花\
"and didn't love me wholeheartedly."
♪ 难望我再归家里
"I am furious."
♪ 气难下
"Don't expect me to go home."
♪ 寂寞深宵思想你
"I think of you on lonely nights."
♪ 徘徊花荫冷雨下
"I walked back and forth in rain ."
♪ 旧梦烟消不堪记
"I hate recalling the old dream."
♪ 怕情话
"I'm afraid of sweet nothings."
♪ 望你将哥宽恕吧
"Please forgive me."
♪ 望你速速归我家
"I hope you can go home soon."
♪ 缘份已了一刀断
"The lot which brought us together" "was gone."
♪ 我泪流下
"My tears fall down."
好
No way.
你不返来
It's meaningless for me
我做人还有甚么意义呢
to stay in this world without you.
哈哈哈
Ha. . .
人家那样伤心，难为你还笑得落的
I am so upset, how can you laugh?
♪ 你泪落滔滔我哈哈笑，哈哈哈…
"I am happy to see you cry. Ha. . ."
♪ 情场夫妻算了吧
"We are married. Don't be so mean."
♪ 断绝夫妻的恩爱
"We had a clear break."
♪ 气难下
"I am angry about it."
♪ 任我娇妻点责骂
"You can scold me whatever way you like."
♪ 任我娇妻将我打
"You can hit me whatever way you like."
♪ 你诚实忏悔我归家去
"If you really feel regret, l'll go home."
♪ 快来吧
"Let's go home."
你肯原谅我了？
You forgive me, don't you?
只要你以后别扔下我、不理我
If only you won't leave me alone!
我发毒誓，我以后都不会
I swear! I'll never do it again!
不准你发毒誓
Stop it!
人家又不是不信你
I do believe you!
那样你即是还爱我呀
Then you mean you still love me.
你笑人的
You are teasing me!
阿妈…  我记得奇哥是谁了
Mom . . . I remember who is Keith!
奇哥就是我爸
He is Keith, my dad!
阿爸，你今晚就睡在这儿吧
Dad, you can sleep here.
我帮你收拾好地方了
I've clean up for you.
不过黑漆漆
But don't fool around
你一个人别周围乱走呀
at night.
为甚么不能四围乱走呀？  这间屋有鬼呀？
Why? ls it haunted?
因为这间屋
Because, there are many traps in this house.
有好多机关的
this house is so strange.
你不觉得人也很怪吗？
Don't you think the people are strange too?
你去哪呀？
Where are you going?
阿爸  晚安
Dad! Good night!
你为甚么你用这种眼神望住我呀
Why you look so odd?
见回你，我觉得好幸福呀
I feel lucky to reunite with you .
为甚么我不觉得好幸福？
But I don't have such feeling!
看在奇哥份上
For the sake of Keith.
以后你就做我近身丫环
You can be my maid.
丫环？
Maid .
你是不是跟奇哥有染？
Do you have any affair with Keith?
没有就最好啦
If so,
有的话让我知道你就死了
you'd be in deep trouble
我不敢了，前辈
I dare not, master!
不是前辈，是少奶
You'd not call me master
还是大那个
but madam!
是大少奶
Yes, madam!
周身贱格
Lamebrain!
别吓我呀
Don't scare me!
我好怕黑的
I'm afraid of darkness!
奇哥，今日天气那样好
What a good weather!
我们出去扑蝶吧  扑蝶？
- Let's go out to catch butterfly. - Butterfly?
我先去换件衫
I'll go for a change first.
我换件衫
I come to repair
你去床上
your bed .
你坐在床上，我叫你动你就动
Sit on the bed,
等我听下哪个弹簧有事
follow my instruction.
知道吗？
So I can check the spring.
是，小姐
Yes, miss.
坐过来
Come here.
黄小姐，你怎么打扮得像丫环似的？
How come you look like a maid?
是呀，她们现在收留了我做妹仔呀
They take me as their maid!
那我们怎么呀？
So, what'll we do?
她们两个现在对我很信任
They trust me now!
今晚等她们睡了之后
When they fall asleep tonight.
我们静消消溜走
We can escape.
怎么走呀？
How? Can you see
你没见她们昨晚关上大闸吗
there is a big gate?
你没见她心口挂了条钥匙的吗？
Can you see there's a key hanging around her neck?
震得了
You can move now.
为甚么他睡在这儿？
Why are you sleeping here?
放心
Don't worry,
我整晚者在这里
I'll go with you tonight.
♪ 忽隐又忽现
♪ 流连花丛间
♪ 你如此多恋
♪ 嬉戏不成眠
♪ 何时才疲倦
♪ 不飞舞狩猎
♪ 我不能了解
♪ 总是暗伤悲
♪ 你像只蝴蝶在天上飞
♪ 飞来飞去飞不到我身边
♪ 我只能远远痴痴望著你
♪ 盼啊望啊你能歇 一歇
♪ 你像只蝴蝶在天上飞
♪ 飞来飞去飞不到我身边
♪ 我只能日日夜夜等著你
♪ 想啊念啊你能停一会儿
喂，干嘛偷人家的信呀？
Why do you steal other's letter?
这封信是我的
My letter!
信是你的？你住哪儿呀？
You mean you letter? Where do you live?
回警署
You live here? What prove do you have?
夜叉…告诉阿Sir
Go to the police station.
我是在楼上住
Jinx. . . l live upstairs.
他都不认得你，回警署
He doesn't know you ,
夜叉…
Go to the police station now!
奇哥…奇哥，我捉到了
Brother Keith, l've got it.
我今天好开心呀
I'm so happy!
我知道你是真心爱我的
I know you love me so much .
我决定嫁给你  嫁我？
- I want to marry you. - Marry me?
好，  这次等你进来就一棍打晕你
You'll be fainted this time!
好辛苦呀，开门呀  开门呀
Open the door. . .
你又干甚么呀？
What are you doing?
没有，还你棍子  晚安
To return you this. Good night.
发神经
Crazy!
明天另想个主意，再来
I'll try with another trick.
黄小姐…
Miss Wong . . .
我知道总开关在哪里
I know where the main switch is.
我们现在去偷她的钥匙
We'll go to steal her keys.
为甚么黄小姐的身子那么震呀？
Why is she trembling?
为甚么我的心卜卜跳呀？
My heart beasts so fast!
我真的喜欢你  给我一个机会
I really love you. Please give me a chance.
他这么做
He's doing this kind of thing to me.
我为何一点反应都没有呀？
Why haven't I felt any bad feeling?
难道我真的喜欢他？
Am I really fond of him?
好呀，她终于接受我了
Bravo! She accepts me!
等我出去四周围看一看
I'll go & have a look.
那晚在我家里拿著根蔗那人
Are you the one who appeared in my home that night,
是不是你呀？
holding the sugar cane?
既然让你知道
Since you know it,
等我救你出去之后
after I save you out. . .
我一定杀了你灭口
I'll kill you.
你躲在这儿干嘛呀？
Why do you hide here?
黄小姐，没人了，走快两步  来啦，快点啦
Come, no body's here!
走快两步没人发觉
Hurry up!
阿爸，你有得玩也不叫我一起玩
Why don't you let me join your game, daddy?
不是吧，那么晚了玩捉迷藏
But it's too late.
我要玩
I want it!
那么晚了
Miss, it's late.
不如我们玩睡觉吧
Why don't we play sleeping?
是呀，你现在回房间睡觉
Yeah, go to your room and sleep.
我不玩睡觉，晚晚都睡觉
I don't want sleeping!
那你想玩甚么呀？
So what do you like to play?
一二三红绿灯
"One, Two, Three, Freeze", OK?
那么吵
We can't play such a noisy game.
那么晚不能玩的
It's too late!
我要玩
What game can we play then?
我们玩偷钥匙吧
Let's steal the keys!
好呀，偷钥匙
OK! Bravo!
偷谁的钥匙呢？
Whose key?
偷你妈的钥匙，走吧
Your mom's keys! Let's go!
太好了
Bravo! We've got your key!
偷了你的钥匙也不知道
You didn't notice it.
你干嘛偷我的钥匙呀？
Why do you steal my key?
笨蛋！
You are stupid!
我失败了  我彻底失败了
I fail! I fail completely!
妈不要这样了
Don't do that,
爸和你玩一下而已
daddy wants to play with you only.
本来，我偷那钥匙
Actually, l want to steal the key. . .
就是想出去  去买一只戒指来和你成亲的
because I want to go out, to buy a wedding ring.
真的？
Really?
是呀
Yes.
你看他，蛇头鼠眼的
Look at him, he is cunning!
对呀，一定不是好人
You can tell he is a bad egg.
三位，要不要喝点甚么？
Would you like something to drink?
艳芳呀，飘红干嘛叫你阿妈呀？
Why Piu Hung call you mom?
医生说她越来越疯了
The doctor said she is crazy.
别理她吧
So let her go.
你们千万别拆穿了她呀
Don't teIl her the truth.
这样只会刺激了她
Or it will stimulate her.
你好，我叫飘红  我叫飘红呀
How are you, l am Piu Hung.
有空约我出来谈一下生意吧，雷老总
Mr. Lui , call me if you are free.
我不是雷老总
I am not Mr. Lui , I am 1 3th Aunt.
我是十三姨呀！
You are the girlfriend of Wong Fei-hong. Glad to meet you . . .
我有空上广州探你吧
I'll visit you in Canton later.
她说了什么？
What did she say?
为何你的朋友们
Why do your friends
都凶神恶煞的？
look so vicious?
尤其那个
Especially that one.
他们当年都是绿林大盗
They were the notorious thieves.
你讲的那个就叫做万人斩
The one you mentioned is called Butcher.
他以前不是这样的
He wasn't like that,
自从他儿子刺青  在城寨被警察打死以后
after his son shou-chi was shot dead by the cops,
他就变成这样了
he became more and more vicious.
他岂不恨死了警察？
He hates cop, doesn't he? All of them hate cops.
干嘛？你又不是警察！
What are you doing? You are not cop!
喂，你去那儿？开席啦！  去厕所呀  一会再去吧！
- Where are you going? - To the toilet.
开席了
It's dinner time.
Congratulation. . .
随便坐
Take your seat.
欢迎光临，酒微菜薄，招呼不到
Welcome, please help yourself.
大家干杯！
Cheers!
虽然疯了，还算有条理
Although she is crazy, she seems to be normal sometimes.
谢谢大家多年来的努力
After the hardship contributed by all of you,
令本公司的业务蒸蒸日上
our company is going better and better.
恰巧今天是本公司一百三十周年纪念
Today is the 1 30th anniversary of our company,
大家要玩得开心一点
let's enjoy ourselves tonight.
吃完饭还有抽奖呢，大家喝杯呀
There will be lucky draw after dinner, cheers.
好呀……
Cheers, thank you. . .
来  正本
Come on. . .Cheers!
妈！我升做总经理了
Mom, I was promoted to General Manager, are you happy?
你开不开心呀？
Are you happy?
哗！她真的疯成这样子
She is so sick!
那个混蛋又迟到了！
That jerk is late again!
是不是在说你的小儿子阿华呀？
- You mean your son , Wah? - Yes.
和一些流氓在一起
goes with some rascals,
还给自己起了个混号
He gave a nick name himself.
你做甚么？  我来了
- What are you doing? - I am coming.
对不起，对不起，我又迟到
Sorry, I am late.
爸，我先罚自己三杯
I drink 3 as punishment.
这个怎么喝呀，帮我开了它
Open it.
快点呀
- Hurry up! - Great!
你怎么现在才到呀
It's boring to wait you.
我们敬新人三杯
Let us toast to the couple.
起来呀！起来喝呀
Get up!
我在找东西
I am searching for something,
你们自己先喝，别等我
you drink first,
不行…我们等你
No, we'll wait for you.
你慢慢找吧
Take your time.
我要找很久呢
I'll search for a long time.
如果让夜叉爆露了  吕Sir的身份出来
If Lui's identity is disclosed,
那我们就死定了
we'll be dead meat.
有办法！有办法……
I've got an idea.
毒哑你！
To make you dumb!
各位，来干杯…
Cheers. . .
干杯…
- Where are you? - Cheers.
原来是……
Oh, you are. . .
没用，浪费食物！滚开吧
What's the matter with you? You are wasting it. Get lost.
华仔呀，你认识他吗？
Do you know him?
我认识！
Sure.
你甚么？
What?
你说大声一点！
- Speak louder. - What did he say?
对啦
Yes.
他不会写字的
He is illiterate.
他有枪？！
He has a gun?
他是神枪手？
He is a gun man?
他是一个受人尊敬的神枪手！
He is a gun man who is respected?
他是受人尊敬的神枪手
He is a respectable gun man?
因为他受过军事训练！
Because he is military trained .
我知道了！他一定是大圈仔
I know, he must be coming from Mainland China.
这是甚么呀？  讲呀！
- What is it? - Speak up!
甚么？
What?
两只手指
2 fingers.
两个字！
2 words.
第二个字！
The 2nd one.
第二个是人字！对吗？
Isn't it C?
喂，你去那里？
Where are you going?
我在找一张椅子
I am searching for a chair.
继续呀
- What? - Go on . . .
第一个是甚么字呀？
What about the 1 st one?
捉人？
B?
抓人？
D?
初人！
E!
我明白！我明白！
What is it?
插人！
WC!
是甚么呀？
What is it?
你说是甚么呢？  这样这样的呀
Hurry. Tell us.
到底是甚么人呢？  西人？  是鬼婆呀？  有很大的胸脯
- Before Christ? - Jesus?
像打过针似的
Isn't it Christian?
大家静一静……
Wait. . .
我是警察第六场Take7
"I am a PC", scene 2, take 2.
原来你是……  不错！
- Oh you are. . . - Yes.
三位年青人真是非常聪明
You are really smart!
我不用隐瞒大家
This is my real identity.
这一个就是我真正的身份
I've been doing this job for over 20 years.
我是一个艺人
I am an artist
艺人！  过奖……
- I always act as PC, - Thanks. . .
大家请回座位吧
Please have your dinner.
我等一会儿给大家签个名  好呀……
I will send you all my autograph.
有空给我电话
CaIl me if you have time.
你好呀，Auntie  再见！
- Thank you. - See you. . .
女儿呀，你还不睡？
Why don't you sleep?
收拾一下，把合欢酒倒进来
Clean up, and bring me some wine.
奇哥，我们早点休息吧
Let's go to rest now.
救我呀……  还不来？
- Help me. . . - Come on!
来
I am coming!
七步迷晕丹
Hocus!
姐姐，我也想喝合欢酒呀
Sister, l want the wine.
七步迷晕丹，弄晕你们俩母女
Hocus, to make you two faint!
奇哥，我先去换衣服，很快就回来了
I'll go and get change first, I'll be right back.
你最好别回来
I wish you never come back.
为何我吕奇的命这么苦呢？
Why am l so poor?
是张Sir呀
Are you Superintendent Cheung?
我是重案组沙展吕奇呀
I am Sgt. Lui.
我现在在黑玫瑰家里
I am in Black Rose's home.
她们的地址就是……
Her address is. . .
说甚么呀？  甚么事？
- What are you saying? - What is it?
要一客西多士，两客肠仔蛋
He orders 1 dish of spareribs and 2 dishes of chicken legs with rice.
神精病
Crazy!
那个女的到那儿去了？
Where is the woman?
大哥，那女的打晕了我
She made me faint.
现在不知道去了那里呀！
I don't know where she is now.
没用
Idiot!
喂，我是
Speaking.
我想那女的  一定是去了黑玫瑰家里找朋友
I think she is going to the joint of the Black Rose.
你说
Go ahead .
天水围二十八号  木棉小径
Tin Shui Wai , no. 28 Cotton lane.
好！我现在立刻找些兄弟去杀了她们
OK, I'll ask my fellows to kill them .
黎Sir，我不会忘记你的好处
Superintendent Lai , I won't forget you.
就这样
Bye.
听住，叫所有手足
Listen, gather our men
十分钟之后在停车场集合  是！
- in the car park in 1 0 minutes. - Yes.
我不知道，我晕倒了
I don't know, l fainted.
我的车子呢？
Where is my car?
大少爷，大少奶，合欢酒呀
Sir, madam, the wine.
利利是是  谢谢大少奶
- Lucky money. - Thank you.
我们喝一杯，来吧
Come on.
一不离二呀
- Cheer. - One more.
为甚么这么久还没晕呢？
Why? They don't even feel dizzy!
三杯都倒了，还会醉？
How can you feel dizzy?
我们先别进洞房
Shall we postpone the wedding,
将婚期押后三五七年行吗？
maybe make it 7 years later?
你是不是在外面瞒住我藏了个女人？
Are you having any mistress?
事实上我真的有了第二个女人
Actually, l do have another woman .
我妈妈自小帮我定了一门亲事
My mom has arranged a wife for me.
你不用诸多籍口！
No excuse.
叫你妈妈出来见我
Ask your mom to see me.
我妈出不来见你
I can't!
她去了买咸鸭蛋呀！  你放过我啦！
She passed away. Let me go!
我不理你这么多呀
I won't care.
进了我的门就是我的人了
You are my man.
你不要过来呀
Don't come over.
如果不是我……  我死给你看
Or I . . . I'll suicide.
不识抬举！  敬酒不喝喝罚酒
You should be a man of the world. How dare you refuse?
你给我喝的甚么东西？  没有呀！
- What drink have you given me? - Nothing!
没有？为何喝了以后我会晕呢？
But why do I feel dizzy?
那酒……  你……
The wine. . .You. . .
你去死呀你！
Go to die!
究竟发生了甚么事呀？  为何她们会晕过去？
What happened? Why they feel dizzy?
我想是药性发作了
I think it works.
既然这样，事不宜迟了
So, let's go now.
走啦！
Go!
别走呀！
Don't go!
难道这药真的是过了期的？
Is the medicine expired?
阿娟，你怎么知道我在这里？
Kuen, how do you know I am here?
不要说这么多了，他们杀到了
Cut the crap, they are coming.
谁呀？
Who?
走吧！
Let's go!
别走呀！
Stop!
你……
You . . .
爸爸，今天是你的婚礼
Dad, today is your wedding,
这么快就出来鬼混啦？
how can you fool around so soon?
你为何喘气呀？
What's wrong with you?
我跑过来的嘛
Since I ran here in quick speed.
追逐
Chase. . .
还叫了亲戚朋友来
Your relatives arrive.
别动！
Stop!
我不认识他们的
I don't know them.
你为何不把机关的门关上呀？
Why don't you turn off the switch of the trap?
我又不在这里住
I am not living here, how do I know the trap?
我怎么知道有机关？
Get out!
怎么进来的？出去
How did we get here? Go. Be quick.
走快点呀
Hurry.
- Be quick. - Hurry.
来啦，快点啦，这边呀，这边呀！
Come on, this way. . .
不对……  应该这边！
- No, that way. . . - That way.
喂，不用呀！还不用靠岸！
- Don't rush. - Are you fine?
我全身最漂亮的屁股
My beautiful buttocks,
竟然被他打到开花
is ruined by them!
前辈，你们的真传迷晕丹  的解药究竟是甚么呀？
What is the traditional solution to the hocus?
原来你呀……
Oh you. . .
前辈，这个时候你千万不能晕呀……
Don't faint. . .
我们全靠你啦
We all depend on you!
解药就是清……
The solution is clear. . .
清？究竟是清甚么呢？
Clear? What is it?
走开！
- Get lost! - Yes!
你为何这么开心？淫娃
Why are you so happy?
别那么吵啦，你先救醒她吧
Stop quarrelling, wake her up first.
快点
Hurry up!
我不发火你当我是甚么？
You treat me as nothing?
玩剑？！让你见识见识玫瑰剑啦
I'll let you see my Rosy stances.
醒呀……  这个铃不能摇呀
- Wake up. . . - You can't shake it.
这个铃不能摇呀！这个铃不能摇呀！
No. You can't shake it.
我死也要耍完这套拳
I have to finish the stance first.
我去帮忙！
I'll go and help!
吕Sir你怎么样呀？
How are you?
打死我了  怎么样？你没有事呀？  死啦…死啦
- I am hurt! - What's the matter with him?
为何你的样子这么像奇哥呀？！
Why? You look like Keith!
甚么？爸爸对吗？
What? Is it dad?
我是个孤儿
My dad died a long time ago.
师姐，你怎么样？
How are you?
师姐，原来你已经好了
Are you OK?
你们将她扶到一边  我出去应付他们
Step aside, l'll fix them.
大哥，怎么样？
How are you, Boss?
大胆狂徒，竟敢走进玫瑰庄捣乱？
How dare you making trouble here?
我巫良要人死
No one can escape
没有人可以留到天光  开枪！
if I want him die. Fire!
怪只怪我学艺未精
I should blame myself only.
始终中了你的子弹
Cause l was shot.
不过还好只是衣服罢了
But luckily, my clothe is shot.
哗，真的好像粤语长片一样？
It's like Cantonese action film.
不止呢，还会如来神掌呢
She knows Super Palm!
不是如来神掌
It isn't!
是玫瑰秘笈里面的轰天雷
It's the Super Strike Palm of the Rosy Book.
当年她就是练这种内家气功
She got crazy because
练傻了的
of practising this kind of kung-fu .
如果我能像她这样，多好
If I can be that crazy as her, that's good.
你傻了呀？
Are you crazy?
怎么会喜欢做傻子呢？  不要吵呀
You can't become crazy whenever you like to be.
最少这几年
Shut up!
她不用像我这样清醒
At least, I won't be that painful.
整天挂著那个负心的人
I won't miss that heartless guy.
我要杀死你！
I want to kill you .
弟子飘红无意冒犯师傅
You, student doesn't want to offend you.
请师傅多多恕罪！
Please forgive me.
放下我师傅的神主牌！
Leave it down.
竟敢冒犯我师傅的神主牌！
How dare you offend my master's spirit tablet.
你真是不知死活了！
You'd be dead meat.
女侠，饶命呀！
Please forgive me.
今天我飘红要从新做人
I want to turn a new leaf.
前辈，我很感谢你赏识我
I am glad you are appreciating me.
我真的不是你心目中的那个奇哥
But I am not your Keith.
是呀，前辈，最多我们帮你找回他
Yes. Maybe we'll help you to find him .
住嘴！  我不会信你的
Shut up! I won't believe you.
我第一个就杀了你
OK, I'll kill you now.
何必呢？  勉强没有好结果的
It's nonsense. You'd better not to push anyone.
奇哥当天就是这样被我们迫走的
That's why Keith was scared by us and left us.
师姐，我疯了二十几年
Sister, l have got crazy over 20 years.
你一直那么好照顾著我
You have taken care of me over these years.
今天我醒来了
Now, I wake up,
这下半生  我也不知道怎样报答你才好！
I don't know how to pay for it.
你是有点像他
You are like him .
只可惜欠了点风采
But you are not as charming as him .
我真的不是他
I am not.
你这样的货色  只适合她了
And your style. . .only suit her.
谢谢前辈成全
Thank you.
师姐，看来师父这间祖屋
I think the house of our master,
我们不可以继续住下去了
is no longer suitable for us to live.
不如走吧
Let's go.
后会有期！
See you later.
这粤语长片是真的
Are we really in a Cantonese action film?
梦中的公主已睡醒了
The sleeping princess woke up
变成美丽的皇后
& became the queen.
蝴蝶，我祝你永远幸福快乐
I wish you ever lucky & happy.
如果你肯讲童话故事给我听
If you tell me some fairy tales.
我一定很快乐
I'll be happy!
很幸福…
A prince and a princess. . .